Campus Construction; Collection ua950.005
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Photographs, 1964-1973; 257 items
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Campus lake looking Westerly from the East side of the lake., 1964 June 10
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Campus lake looking Westerly from the East side of the lake., 1964 June 10
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The seconf floor foyer of the Infirmary building, facing East., 1966 June 21
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Infirmary building facing North., 1966 June 21
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Business Administration building, facing the North-East from the Social Sciences podium., 1966 June 21
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The first floor interior of the Infirmary building, showcasing the South and East hallways., 1966 June 21
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The first floor foyer of the Infirmary building, facing West., 1966 June 21
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. A panormic view from the corner of the Biology and Chemistry buildings roof, facing North., 1965 June 23
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Fine Arts building facing West from the Earth Sciences building, showing the first floor slab., 1965 June 23
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Biology building looking from the second floor of the Chemistry building, facing North-East to South-West., 1964 June 9
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The basement of the Chemistry building, looking from the North-wWest to toward the South-East., 1964 June 9
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Humanities building looking from South-East to North-West., 1964 June 9
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus.The East-side of the Biology building., 1964 June 9
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Biology building roof looking Northeast., 1965 June 9
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The South-East corner of the Chemistry building featuring the positioning of the exterior column., 1965 June 9
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus, part 1. Fountain at the North of Student-Faculty building facing West., 1966 June 9
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The third floor of the North-East corner room of the Humanities building, facing South., 1966 June 9
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus, part 1. Fountain in the North court of Student-Faculty building facing the West., 1966 July 11
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. Looking North towards the step ramp construction from the Southeast corner of the Greenhouse., 1968 July 22
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The basement of the Infirmary building along the machine room., 1966 July 25
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The second floor center of the Infirmary building showing the steel frame and cabinets., 1966 July 25
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Infirmary building looking North-East, showing the podia., 1966 July 25
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. Looking East from the roof of the Library, the Adminstration building is to the left., 1966 July 25
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Humanities building with the heating tunnel in the foreground., 1964 July 7
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Biology building and podium overhang on the East-side, showing the waterproofing of the podium., 1965 July 8
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Biology building interior, the second floor's South-West corridor showing lab cabinets roughed in., 1965 July 8
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Chemistry building facing the North-West., 1964 August 10
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Biology building with detail of the podium wall showing the forms, facing East., 1964 August 10
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Infirmary site clearing looking North along the Southern section., 1965 August 10
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Infirmary site clearing, looking East across the Northern section., 1965 August 10
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Infirmary site clearing, looking West across the Northern section., 1965 August 10
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Infirmary site clearing, looking South along the Southern section., 1965 August 10
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The ground floor of the Infirmary building along the drug dispensary., 1966 August 24
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The parking area and walkway on the South-side of the Infirmary building, facing East., 1966 August 24
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The North hall on the second floor of the Infirmary building, facing West., 1966 August 24
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The pavement at the front entrance and walkway of the Infirmary building, facing East., 1966 August 24
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The interior of the Fine Arts gallery facing South., 1967 August 28
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Infirmary site and foundation looking East across the Northern section., 1965 September 16
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Infirmary site and foundation, looking West across the Northern section., 1965 September 16
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Infirmary site and foundation, looking North along the Southern section., 1965 September 16
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Infirmary site and foundation, looking South along the Southern section., 1965 September 16
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus, part 2. Panorama from roof of University Library looking east., 1965 September 23
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Business Adminstration building at its West end, taken from the Library roof., 1965 September 23
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Biology building East-side looking Southwesterly at the podium wall., 1964 September 8
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The interior of the Biology building at ground level, showing mechanicals, facing South-West., 1964 September 8
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. Top of the Chemistry roof and court between the Chemistry and Biology buildings., 1965 September 9
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. An aerial shot of the main campus., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Campus lake flood that poured into Western Avenue., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Campus lake flood that poured into Western Avenue., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Campus lake flood that poured into Western Avenue., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Campus lake flood that poured into Western Avenue., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Campus lake flood that poured into Western Avenue., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Campus lake flood that poured into Western Avenue., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Campus lake flood that poured into Western Avenue., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Campus lake flood that poured into Western Avenue., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Campus lake flood that poured into Western Avenue., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Campus lake flood that poured into Western Avenue., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Campus lake flood that poured into Western Avenue., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Campus lake flood that poured into Western Avenue., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Campus lake flood that poured into Western Avenue., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Campus lake flood that poured into Western Avenue., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Campus lake flood that poured into Western Avenue., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Campus lake flood that poured into Western Avenue., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Campus lake flood that poured into Western Avenue., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Campus lake flood that poured into Western Avenue., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Campus lake flood that poured into Western Avenue., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Campus lake flood that poured into Western Avenue., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Campus lake flood that poured into Western Avenue., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Campus lake flood that poured into Western Avenue., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Campus lake flood that poured into Western Avenue., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Campus lake flood that poured into Western Avenue., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Campus lake flood that poured into Western Avenue., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Campus lake flood that poured into Western Avenue., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Campus lake flood that poured into Western Avenue., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Campus lake flood that poured into Western Avenue., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Campus lake flood that poured into Western Avenue., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Campus lake flood that poured into Western Avenue., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Campus lake flood that poured into Western Avenue., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Campus lake flood that poured into Western Avenue., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Campus lake flood that poured into Western Avenue., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Campus lake flood that poured into Western Avenue., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Campus lake flood that poured into Western Avenue., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Campus lake flood that poured into Western Avenue., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Campus lake flood that poured into Western Avenue., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Campus lake flood that poured into Western Avenue., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Campus lake flood that poured into Western Avenue., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Campus lake flood that poured into Western Avenue., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Campus lake flood that poured into Western Avenue., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Campus lake flood that poured into Western Avenue., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Campus lake flood that poured into Western Avenue., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The groundbreaking of the Freedom Quad, from left to right Stanley Isnlim(sp????) of the University Council, President Vincent O'Leary, and Mayor Thomas Whalen., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The Residence Hall, Dutch Quad incompleted sometime around 1964, featuring the a completed Beverwyck and incpmpleted Schyler buildings, South of Western Avenue., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. The inside of the Performing Arts Center as a stage is being assembled., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. An aerial shot of the main campus., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. A crane on top of an unidenitifed tower in the middle of a Quad., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. An aerial shot of the main campus., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. A crane on top of the Campus Center's dome., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. An aerial shot of the Main Campus amidst the on-going construction of the mid-1960s., Undated
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. A view of the dome outside the Campus Center from the ground looking up, showing the scaffolding., 1968 January 1
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus. An aerial view of the main campus, featuring an unfinished fountain in the center., 1965 January 1
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus, part 1. University Library interior being inspected by R. Morris Dean., ca. 1967
  - Construction of the University at Albany's main campus. Aerial photograph of the uptown campus., ca. 1967 January
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus, part 1. Main entrance of the University Library., 1966 January 10
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus, part 1. University Library view from the first floor of the Education building facing north., 1965 January 11
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus, part 1. University Library facing west., 1965 October 12
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus, part 1. University Library building capital form showing troughs, wiring and rods., 1964 October 9
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus, part 1. University Library building site of the Library basement and first floor pillars., 1964 November 10
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus, part 1. University Library basement showing capitals with light troughers., 1964 November 10
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus, part 1. University Library looking east between the Library and Education buildings., 1965 November 8
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus, part 1. University Library and Education buildings from the Physics podium., 1965 November 8
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus, part 1. University Library main entrance from the northeast., 1966 February 10
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus, part 1. University Library third floor from southwest corner., 1966 February 10
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus, part 1. University Library facing northeast, Education Building., 1965 February 11
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus, part 1. University Library building site., 1965 April 10
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus, part 1. University Library first floor of southeast wing stairs and tall columns outside., 1965 May 10
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus, part 1. Facing north in the University Library lobby., 1966 May 11
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus, a cart of materials and a sign for University Architect Edward Durell Stone., 1973 May 14
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus, part 1. University Library building site from west., 1964 May 6
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus, part 1. University Library building site., 1964 June 9
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus, part 1. University Library looking west into court, showing stairs and columns., 1965 June 9
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus, part 1. University Library southern side showing the podium, pre-cast panels and overhang forming., 1965 June 9
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus, part 1. Main entrance of the University Library., 1966 June 9
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus, part 1. Third floor of the north side of the University Library., 1966 June 9
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus, part 1. University Library basement, looking north in a large storeroom., 1966 July 11
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus, part 1. University Library entrance lobby facing northwest., 1966 July 11
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus, part 1. Entrance lobby of the University Library., 1966 July 14
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus, part 1. Library stack area., 1966 July 14
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus, part 1. University Library interior facing east from the second floor., 1965 July 8
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus, part 1. University Library southeast corner overhang panel., 1965 July 8
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus, part 1. University Library dome over entrance court facing east., 1966 August 7
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus, part 1. University Library building site facing south., 1964 September 10
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus, part 1. University Library entrance, hanging stairs, under dome facing southwest., 1966 September 17
  - Construction of the University at Albany's academic buildings on the uptown campus, part 1. University Library ground level facing southeast., 1964 September 8
  - Construction of the University at Albany's main campus. Lecture Halls Foundation, looking East from Library Podium, 1996-03-21
  - Aerial photograph of the Albany Country Club prior to the construction of the Uptown Campus. Sent to Walter Tisdale, Assistant to the President, labeled "New Site, 1st picture", 1960 October 9 (Oversized 1)
- University Building Planning, Correspondence (1 of 2), 1955-1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- University Building Planning, Correspondence (2 of 2), 1960-1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Planning, Buildings, 1958-1964 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- New York State Normal College Architectural Blueprints, 1906-1908
  - New York State Normal College blueprint, auditorium building. Subbasement plan, drawing number 57, 1907 July 16
    Traced from original by W.L. and H.L in 1931 May 19.
  - New York State Normal College blueprint, auditorium building. Basement, first floor, mezzanine floor and ceiling plan, and roof plan, drawing number 58, 1907 July 16
    Traced from original drawings by M.S. in 1931 May 14.
  - New York State Normal College blueprint, auditorium building. Elevations, drawing number 59, 1907 July 18
  - New York State Normal College blueprint, one half plan of west pavilion of eastern peristyle. drawing number 60, 1907 July 16
  - New York State Normal College blueprint, auditorium building. Engineering drawing, drawing number 69, 1906 July 17
  - New York State Teachers College blueprint, boiler house. Plan below grade, drawing number 81, 1907 October 12
    Traced from original drawings by G.L.F. in 1927 April 6.